Daniel Becker | Web Development

Denver, CO 80204 (303) 859-1719

dbecker92691@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/richard-daniel-becker https://github.com/dbecker92691 https://www.danielbecker.rocks

Professional Summary

- 3+ years in the tech industry, building media and marketing programs for a large-scale company
- Built and implemented four diverse training programs to educate new recruits for a a variety of positions within a large scale company

Skills

React | Ruby on Rails | JavaScript | Node.JS | Express | Java | JQuery | MongoDB | SQL | Python |

Administrative Systems like Active Admin | ZenDesk | Salesforce | Data Analytics | Doubleclick For Publishers

Quality Control Analysis | Communications and Media | Project Management and Feature Development

Education

Bachelor of Arts: Culinary & Hospitality Management The Art Institute of Colorado Denver, CO

Web Development Certificate General Assembly Denver, CO

Experience

Web Development Immersive, General Assembly, Denver, CO

Sep 2018 −Dec 2018

- Created several full stack applications using React, Node.JS, Express, Ruby/Sinatra, SQL,MongoDB.
- Built interactive web pages using JQuery, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap.
- Completed projects can be seen at https://www.danielbecker.rocks or https://github.com/dbecker92691

Lead Technical Analyst, *Ibotta*, Denver, CO

Aug 2017 — Sep 2018

- Managed 65-million-dollar budget annually in marketing programs.
- Developed and implemented processes for technical analyst team in core business activity.
- Provided information expertise for internal departments including marketing, client success, client partnerships, engineering, and product.
- Participated in development of special side projects including Native In-app Video program and new-hire training.
- Analyzed shopper data and information to produce targeting principles by breaking down client requests and applying them to shopper purchasing data.
- Used computer systems such as Active Admin, Google Doubleclick for Publishers, Salesforce, Looker and MySQL to set up daily app functions.
- Established dozens of long-range objectives and specified strategies such as implementing a ticketing system and error tracking to achieve a team wide accuracy rate of 98%.
- Interviewed, selected, and hired 3 Jr. Technical Analysts into the organization.
- Kept up-to-date on 5-10 database management programs a year to apply the latest processes and keep our app running smoothly.

Media Content Specialist (contract), Viewster, Berlin, Germany

Sept 2016 - Jan 2017

- Sourced and created social media content including; image and video content, written content and blog content.
- Adjusted and coordinated dozens of social media posts to meet strict client deadlines.
- Made decisions based on personal judgement and considered the relative costs and benefits of clients to choose the most appropriate media solution.

Technical Analyst, *Ibotta*, Denver, CO

Sept 2015 - Aug 2017

- Responsible for the day to day creation and maintenance of rebates within the Ibotta application.
- Provide a strong technical support system for the Client Success Team including, low level data analytics, ad server structure and marketing structure.
- Conducted quality control tests, analysis, and inspections of over 500 monthly campaign's quality and performance.
- Kept up-to-date on 5-10 database management programs a year to apply the latest processes and keep our app running smoothly.
- Used computer systems such as Active Admin, Google Doubleclick for Publishers, Salesforce, Looker and MySQL to set up daily app functions.
- Analyzed shopper data and information to produce targeting principles by breaking down client requests and applying them to shopper purchasing data.

Customer Support Representative, Akraya (Ibotta contractor), Denver, CO

Apr 2015 - Sept 2015

- Analyzed and respond to hundreds of email inquiries per day from users.
- Worked through fraud reports, receipt moderation, and customer emails.
- Reviewed systems and customer accounts to resolve issues.

- Worked on special projects for senior management team in marketing, sales & technology.
- Maintained a service orientation mentality and actively sought ways to support our user base with application issues.
- Troubleshot hundreds of types of cases causing user operating errors and approached them with unique and time saving solutions.

Sandwich Artist/Delivery Driver, Snarf's Sandwiches, Denver, CO

Jan 2014 - Apr 2015

- Worked high volume in-store services as well as large order catering service to Denver area.
- Managed restaurant inventory, by providing a daily item count, placing orders and logging daily food waste.
- Managed daily cash handling such as balancing the register, organizing daily deposits and sorting cash tip balances.
- Kept the store clean and organized with daily task list.

Line Cook, Crave Real Burgers, Highlands Ranch, CO

Oct 2012- Jan 2014

- Grill cook and food expediter for Crave Real Burgers.
- Maintained high culinary standards while delivering food in a timely manner.
- Other responsibilities included general upkeep and organization of the restaurant.

Line Cook, *The Hyatt French Quarter*, New Orleans, LA

Apr 2012 – *Sept* 2012

- Starting employee for the initial opening of the Hyatt French Quarter.
- Provided service for three hotel restaurants, as well as room service and banquet service.
- Other responsibilities included organizing and inventory control.

Line Cook, *Crave Real Burgers*, Castle Rock, CO

Oct 2011-Apr 2012

- Grill cook and food expediter for Crave Real Burgers.
- Maintained high culinary standards while delivering food in a timely manner.
- Other responsibilities included general upkeep and organization of the restaurant.

Assistant Chef, Castle Country Assisted Living, Castle Rock, CO

Oct 2009- Sept 2010

- Responsible for cooking daily meals for residents.
- Making sure all dietary needs were met for any resident.
- Maintaining the quality and organization of the kitchen and dining area.